<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>




	
	
			

	
	
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			
			

	
	
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			
			

	
	
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			
			

	
	
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			
			

	
	
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			
			

	
	
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			
			

	
	
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			
			

	
	
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

	
	
			
			

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Getting Started on CIS 308 Textbook</title>
    <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis308/0-chapter/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Getting Started on CIS 308 Textbook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:53:05 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis308/0-chapter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>VS Code</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis308/0-chapter/0_1-vscode/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:53:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis308/0-chapter/0_1-vscode/</guid>
      <description>VS Code In CIS 308, we will edit our C programs using VS Code with C/C++ extensions. You likely already have Visual Studio (2019 or 2022) installed on your computer from CIS 300 and/or 400 &amp;ndash; however, we will not be using Visual Studio in CIS 308. While it does have a C++ compiler, it behaves differently than more widely accepted C compilers (versions of gcc and clang). Finally, this class has a secondary goal of exposing students to a variety of Unix/Linux tools &amp;ndash; something that cannot be done as easily in Visual Studio.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using git</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis308/0-chapter/0_2-usinggit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:53:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis308/0-chapter/0_2-usinggit/</guid>
      <description>This class will use GitHub links to create initial repositories for both labs and programming projects, similarly to what you have done in CIS 300 and 301.
GitHub account First, you will need to create a GitHub account here. If you already have one, you can use your existing account.
Verify a git install You will likely already have a command-line version of git installed on your machine. To check, open a folder in VS Code, display the integrated terminal, and type:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Compiling and Running</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis308/0-chapter/0_3-compilerun/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:53:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis308/0-chapter/0_3-compilerun/</guid>
      <description>After you have installed VS Code along with gcc, you can write C programs in the VS Code editor and then use the integrated terminal to compile and run.
Hello, World! in VS Code Here is a Hello, World! program written in C using VS Code. It is saved to the file hello.c (note that .c is the extension for C programs):
Find code in terminal To compile and run a C program, make sure the integrated terminal appears below the code in VS Code (as shown above).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Terminal commands</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis308/0-chapter/0_4-terminal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:53:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis308/0-chapter/0_4-terminal/</guid>
      <description>A side goal of this class is for students to become more comfortable with using the terminal. With practice, you will find that you are faster at navigating folders, creating files/folders, compiling/running programs, using tools stuch as git, etc. using the terminal than you are using a GUI. Familiarity with a terminal is especially useful in system administration and web development.
Summary of common terminal commands Here is a summary table of the most common terminal commands for this course:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Debugging C programs</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis308/0-chapter/0_5-debugging/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:53:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis308/0-chapter/0_5-debugging/</guid>
      <description>gdb is the C debugger. It allows you to create an executable specifically for debugging purposes.
Getting gdb First, ensure that you have gdb installed.
gdb on Windows Type in a terminal:
gdb -- version If you see a version number, then you already have gdb installed. If you see an error that gdb is unrecognized, you will need to install it. Launch a MSYS2 prompt (Windows icon-&amp;gt;type MSYS2) and then type the following in MSYS2:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remote Access</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis308/0-chapter/0_6_remoteaccess/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:53:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis308/0-chapter/0_6_remoteaccess/</guid>
      <description>In the case that you are unable (or uninterested) to install some of the C tools on your own machine (such as gcc, gdb, or make), you can install the Remote - SSH extension in VS Code. This will allow you to remotely connect to the CS Linux server, which already has all the C tools installed. You will be able to use VS Code to edit files that are stored on your CS department U: drive the same way that you would edit local files.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>